http://www.gideons.ca/privacy.aspx

Skip to Content
Privacy Policy
The Gideons International In Canada has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy. We hold ourselves accountable before God to protect any information you supply to us. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for our website at www.gideons.ca.
Information Collection and Use
The Gideons International In Canada is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. The Gideons International In Canada collects information from users at several different points on our website.
The Gideons International in Canada provides regular communications to its members & donors through regular postal mail, mobile and/or electronic mail. Any personally identifiable information provided by you will be used for the purpose of delivering the mailing item, renewing your subscription, providing details on your donation(s), the membership program, research and/or marketing. You may choose to opt-out of these communications at any time by contacting 1-888-482-4253 or unsubscribing to an e-mail you've received.
Order
Information is requested from the user on our order form, for the purpose of contact information (like name and shipping address) and financial information (like credit card number, expiration date). This information is used to process customer's orders and for billing purposes. The contact information is also used when we experience difficulty in processing an order.
Cookies
A cookie is a unit of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is not linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. Once the user closes his browser, the cookie terminates. For instance, by setting a cookie on our site, the user would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use our site. The only drawback to this is that the user will be limited in some areas of our site.
Log Files
The Gideons International In Canada uses Internet Protocol addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. Internet Protocol addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.
Sharing
Outside vendors are used in processing credit card information and shipping Scripture orders. We only use companies who agree not to retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. However, The Gideons International In Canada is not responsible for the privacy practices of any such third parties.
We partner with certain third parties to provide specific services. When the user signs up for these services, which will be identified to you before or during the sign-up process, we will share names, or other contact information necessary for the third party to provide these services. These parties have agreed not to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services. However, The Gideons International In Canada is not responsible for the privacy practices of any such third parties.
Notwithstanding the foregoing, we will consider, and may release, individually identifiable information to third parties: (1) to comply with valid legal requirements such as a law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena or court order; or (2) in special cases, such as a physical threat to you or others. Furthermore, The Gideons International In Canada reserves the right to disclose to third parties information about usage of this site and any related services, including information gathered during your use of the site. Any information so disclosed will be in the form of aggregate data (such as overall patterns or demographic reports) that does not describe or identify any individual user.
User Disclosures
Subscribers may have access to certain electronic forums, such as chat rooms, bulletin boards, e-mail lists, or others, to which other subscribers also have access. The Gideons International In Canada does not routinely monitor these forums, and is not responsible for protecting the privacy and confidentiality of any information that you disclose in such a forum.
Links
This website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that The Gideons International In Canada is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. Users are encouraged that when they leave our site they should read the privacy statements of each website that collects personally identifiable information.
Surveys
From time to time, our site requests information from users via surveys. Participation in these surveys is completely voluntary and the user has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as postal code, age level). Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of our ministry.
Security
This website takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the website, the information is protected both online and off-line.
When sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number), is requested from users, that information is protected with the best encryption software presently available in the industry - Secured Socket Layer. [While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Firefox and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to unlocked, or open, when you are just 'surfing'.]
While we use Secured Socket Layer encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also have in place procedures to protect user information off-line. Use of user information is restricted and monitored in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information.
Revised November 2010.
© Copyright 2020 The Gideons International In Canada
